Macy Ma - Senior Front-End Developer

- Name: Macy Ma

- Title: Senior Front-End Developer

- Email: hi@macyma.me

- Visa Status: Work visa application has been submitted

Able to build a whole application from translating requirements to actionable, specific, technical tasks; coding and manage progress. I used to work in Alibaba Group (cofounder Jack Ma) for three years and my position is Senior Front-End Engineer.

Skills

- Programming: JavaScript (ES6+) / HTML5 / CSS3 / TypeScript
- Library & Framework: React / Next.js / jQuery
- Design: Common Design Principles / Sketch / Photoshop / Responsive Web Design
- Tooling: VSCode / Git (GitFlow) / webpack / Babel / Debug (Devtools) / SCSS / Less
- Industry: e-HR and Recruitment / Internationalization

Work experience

Front-End Developer/Freelance (Gap Year) - Jun. 2018 - Jun. 2019

- Coded at home.
- Prepared to immigrate to New Zealand with my husband.
- Traveled.
- Started learning English.

Alibaba Group Holding Limited (https://www.alibabagroup.com/)

Alibaba Group (co-founder Jack Ma) has more than 66,421 full-time employees, like FLAG Companies, only the best of the best in China can join in Alibaba.

I was in the Information Platform Business Unit-User experience Department of Alibaba (now renamed Enterprise Intelligence Department), and I worked as a Front-End Engineer to handle the requirements of Alibaba Recruitment Business from October 2014 to June 2018. Alibaba Recruitment Business includes more than 12 systems serving all Alibaba staff and target candidates.

Senior Front-End Engineer / Aug. 2017 - Jun. 2018

- Led three outsourced employees to start the recruitment internationalization project, completed the internationalization of the Recruitment Workbench System and Overseas Recruitment Official Platform. Made a foundation for the company's internationalization.
- Rebuild the Internal Transfer System.

Front-End Engineer / Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2017

- Mainly created the Recruitment Workbench System which is a recruitment management platform. I completed this project from architecture design to coding.
- Maintained several uxcore components (<u>uxcore</u> is a react componet lib for PC, belongs our team) and started to learn to write unit test.
- Other projects: rebuild the Talent Pool System which is a system that the team leader can find target candidates, and completed the structure interview feature.
- All of these projects use React, Reflux and uxcore lib.

Front-End Intern / Oct. 2014 - May. 2015

- Participated in building the Focus System which is a campus interview system, included Face-to-Face Interview, Telephone Interview and Video Interview. The type of remote interview saves company might 1+ million NZD pre year.
- This project uses jQuery, Backbone and Node.js.
- Familiar with the team's development process, project structure and business.

Open Source Project

- <u>uxcore</u> participant. React component lib for PC. I have maintained several components and wrote the unit test.
- <u>the-javascript/structure</u> partner. Put JavaScript related knowledge in a structural way. Help people learn and verify the skills. I finished the part of front-end and wrote several documents.

Education

Dalian Minzu University, Network Engineering — Bachelor, 2011 - 2015

Links

- GitHub: https://github.com/MacyMa18

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/macy-ma-107887134/